<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<title>National Park Service Boundaries</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>LandsNet - Land Resources Division (LRD)NPS Director's Order #25 states: &amp;quot;Land status maps will be prepared to identify the ownership of the lands within the authorized boundaries of the park unit. These maps, showing ownership and acreage, are the 'official record' of the acreage of Federal and non-federal lands within the park boundaries. While these maps are the official record of the lands and acreage within the unit's authorized boundaries, they are not of survey quality and not intended to be used for survey purposes.&amp;quot; As such this data is intended for use as a tool for GIS analysis. It is in no way intended for engineering or legal purposes. The data accuracy is checked against best available sources which may be dated and vary by location. NPS assumes no liability for use of this data. The boundary polygons LRD creates represent the current legislated boundary of a given NPS unit. NPS does not necessarily have full fee ownership or hold another interest (easement, right of way, etc...) in all parcels contained within this boundary. Equivalently NPS may own or have an interest in parcels outside the legislated boundary of a given unit. In order to obtain complete information about current NPS interests both inside and outside the units’ legislated boundary, the tracts file created by LRD should be used in conjunction with this boundary file created by LRD.Available on NPS Open DataAbraham Lincoln Birthplace National Historic Site, Acadia National Park, Adams National Historical Park, African Burial Ground National Monument, Agate Fossil Beds National Monument, Alagnak Wild River, Alibates Flint Quarries National Monument, Allegheny Portage Railroad National Historic Site, American Samoa, Andersonville National Historic Site, Andrew Johnson National Historic Site, Aniakchak National Monument, Aniakchak National Preserve, Antietam National Battlefield, Apostle Islands National Lakeshore, Appalachian National Scenic Trail, Appomattox Court House National Historical Park, Arches National Park, Arkansas Post National Memorial, Arlington House - Robert E. Lee Memorial, Assateague Island National Seashore, Aztec Ruins National Monument, Badlands National Park, Bandelier National Monument, Belmont-Paul Women's Equality National Monument, Bent's Old Fort National Historic Site, Bering Land Bridge National Preserve, Big Bend National Park, Big Hole National Battlefield, Big Thicket National Preserve, Bighorn Canyon National Recreation Area, Biscayne National Park, Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park, Bluestone National Scenic River, Booker T. Washington National Monument, Boston African American National Historic Site, Boston Harbor Islands National Recreation Area, Boston National Historical Park, Brices Cross Roads National Battlefield Site, Brown v. Board of Education National Historic Site, Bryce Canyon National Park, Buck Island Reef National Monument, Buffalo National River, Cabrillo National Monument, Cadastre Theme, Canaveral National Seashore, Cane River Creole National Historical Park, Canyon de Chelly National Monument, Canyonlands National Park, Cape Cod National Seashore, Cape Krusenstern National Monument, Capitol Reef National Park, Capulin Volcano National Monument, Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site, Carlsbad Caverns National Park, Carter G. Woodson National Historic Site, Casa Grande Ruins National Monument, Castillo de San Marcos National Monument, Castle Clinton National Monument, Castle Mountains National Monument, Catoctin Mountain Park, Cedar Breaks National Monument, Cedar Creek Belle Grove, Cesar E. Chavez National Monument, Chaco Culture National Historical Park, Chamizal National Memorial, Channel Islands National Park, Charles Pinckney National Historic Site, Charles Young Buffalo Soldiers National Monument, Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park, Chickasaw National Recreation Area, Chiricahua National Monument, Christiansted National Historic Site, City of Rocks National Reserve, Clara Barton National Historic Site, Colorado National Monument, Congaree National Park, Constitution Gardens, Coronado National Memorial, Cowpens National Battlefield, Crater Lake National Park, Craters of the Moon National Monument, Cumberland Gap Historical Park, Curecanti National Recreation Area, Cuyahoga Valley National Park, Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park, De Soto National Memorial, Death Valley National Park, Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area, Denali National Park, Denali National Preserve, Department of Interior, Devils Postpile National Monument, Devils Tower National Monument, Dinosaur National Park, Dry Tortugas National Park, Edgar Allen Poe National Historic Site, Edison National Historic Site, Effigy Mounds National Monument, Eisenhower National Historic Site, El Morro National Monument, Eleanor Roosevelt National Historic Site, Eugene O'Neill National Historic Site, Federal Hall National Memorial, First Ladies National Historic Site, First State National Monument, Flight 93 National Memorial, Florissant Fossil Beds National Monument, Ford's Theatre National Historic Site, Fort Bowie National Historic Site, Fort Caroline National Memorial, Fort Davis National Historic Site, Fort Donelson National Battlefield, Fort Frederica National Monument, Fort Laramie National Historic Site, Fort Larned National Historic Site, Fort Matanzas National Monument, Fort McHenry National Monument and Historic Shrine, Fort Monroe National Monument, Fort Necessity National Battlefield, Fort Point National Historic Site, Fort Pulaski National Monument, Fort Scott National Historic Site, Fort Smith National Historic Site, Fort Stanwix National Mounment, Fort Sumter National Monument, Fort Union National Monument, Fort Union Trading Post National Historic Site, Fort Washington Park, Fossil Butte National Monument, Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, Frederick Douglass National Historic Site, Frederick Law Olmsted National Historic Site, Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania County Battlefields Memorial National Military Park, Friendship Hill National Historic Site, Gates of the Arctic National Park, Gates of the Arctic National Preserve, Gateway National Recreation Area, General Grant National Memorial, George Rogers Clark National Historical Park, George Washington Birthplace National Monument, George Washington Carver National Monument, George Washington Memorial Parkway, Gettysburg National Military Park, Gila Cliff Dwellings National Monument, Glacier Bay National Park, Glacier Bay National Preserve, Glacier National Park, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, Golden Gate National Recreation Area, Golden Spike National Historic Site, Governors Island National Monument, Grand Canyon National Park, Grand Portage National Monument, Grand Teton National Park, Grant-Kohrs Ranch National Historic Site, Great Basin National Park, Great Sand Dunes National Park, Great Sand Dunes National Preserve, Greenbelt Park, Guilford Courthouse National Military Park, Gulf Islands National Seashore, Hagerman Fossil Beds National Monument, Haleakala National Park, Hamilton Grange National Memorial, Hampton National Historic Site, Harpers Ferry National Historical Park, Harry S Truman National Historic Site, Hawai'i Volcanoes National Park, Herbert Hoover National Historic Site, Hohokam Pima National Monument, Home of Franklin D Roosevelt National Historic Site, Homestead National Monument, Honouliuli National Monument, Hopewell Culture National Historical Park, Hopewell Furnace National Historic Site, Horseshoe Bend National Military Park, Hot Springs National Park, Hovenweep National Monument, Hubbell Trading Post National Historic Site, Ice Age National Scenic Trail, Independence National Historical Park, Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore, James A Garfield National Historic Site, Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve, Jefferson National Expansion Memorial, Jewel Cave National Monument, Jimmy Carter National Historic Site, John D. Rockefeller, John Day Fossil Beds National Monument, John Fitzgerald Kennedy National Historic Site, John Muir National Historic Site, Johnstown Flood National Memorial, Joshua Tree National Park, Kalaupapa National Historical Park, Kaloko-Honokohau National Historical Park, Katmai National Park, Katmai National Preserve, Kenai Fjords National Park, Kennesaw Mountain National Battlefield Park, Keweenaw National Historic Park, Kings Canyon National Park, Kings Mountain National Military Park, Klondike Gold Rush National Historical Park, Knife River Indian Village National Historic Site, Kobuk Valley National Park, Korean War Veterans Memorial, Lake Chelan National Recreation Area, Lake Clark National Park, Lake Clark National Preserve, Lake Mead National Recreation Area, Lassen Volcanic National Park, Lava Beds National Monument, Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail, Lincoln Boyhood National Memorial, Lincoln Home National Historic Site, Lincoln Memorial, Little Bighorn Battlefield National Monument, Little River Canyon National Preserve, Little Rock Central High School National Historic Site, Longfellow National Historic Site, Lower Saint Croix National Scenic Riverway, Lyndon B. Johnson National Historical Park, Lyndon Baines Johnson Memorial Grove, Maggie L. Walker National Historic Site, Mammoth Cave National Park, Manassas National Battlefield Park, Manhattan Project National Historical Park, Manzanar National Historic Site, Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park, Martin Luther King Jr Memorial, Martin Luther King Jr. National Historic Site, Martin Van Buren National Historic Site, Mary McLeod Bethune Council House National Historic Site, Mesa Verde National Park, Minidoka National Historic Site, Minute Man National Historical Park, Minuteman Missile National Historic Site, Mojave National Preserve, Monocacy National Battlefield, Montezuma Castle National Monument, Moores Creek National Battlefield, Morristown National Historical Park, Mount Rainier National Park, Mount Rushmore National Memorial, Muir Woods National Monument, Natchez National Historical Park, Natchez Trace Parkway, National Capital Parks, National Mall, National Park of American Samoa, Natural Bridges National Monument, Navajo National Monument, New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park, Nicodemus National Historic Site, Ninety Six National Historic Site, Niobrara National Scenic River, Noatak National Preserve, North Cascades National Park, Obed Wild and Scenic River, Ocmulgee National Mounment, Olympic National Park, Oregon Caves National Monument, Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument, Ozark National Scenic Riverway, Padre Island National Seashore, Palo Alto National Historic Site, Paterson Great Falls National Historical Park, Pea Ridge National Military Park, Pecos National Historical Park, Pennsylvania Avenue National Historic Site, Perry's Victory and International Peace Memorial, Petersburg National Battlefield, Petrified Forest National Park, Petroglyph National Monument, Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore, Pinnacles National Park, Pipe Spring National Monument, Pipestone Monument, Piscataway Park, Point Reyes National Seashore, Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial, Prince William Forest Park, Pu'uhonua o Honaunau National Historical Park, Pu'ukohola Heiau National Historic Site, Pullman National Monument, Rainbow Bridge National Monument, Richmond National Battlefield, River Raisin National Battlefield Park, Rocky Mountain National Park, Roger Williams National Memorial, Ronald Reagan Boyhood Home National Historic Site, Rosie the Riveter/World War II Home Front National Historical Park, Ross Lake National Recreation Area, Russell Cave National Monument, Sagamore Hill National Historic Site, Saguaro National Park, Saint Croix Island International Historic Site, Saint Croix National Scenic Riverway, Saint Paul's Church National Historic Site, Saint-Gaudens National Historic Site, Salem Maritime National Historic Site, Salinas Pueblo Missions National Monument, Salt River Bay National Historical Park, San Antonio Missions National Historical Park, San Francisco Maritime National Historical Park, Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site, Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area, Saratoga National Historical Park, Saugus Iron Works National Historic Site, Scotts Bluff National Mounment, Selma to Montgomery National Historic Trail, Sequoia National Park, Shenandoah National Park, Sitka National Historical Park, Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore, Springfield Armory National Historic Site, Statue of Liberty National Monument, Stonewall National Monument, Sunset Crater Volcano National Monument, Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve, Thaddeus Kosciuszko National Memorial, Theodore Roosevelt Birthplace National Historic Site, Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural National Historic Site, Theodore Roosevelt Island National Memorial, Theodore Roosevelt National Park, Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Thomas Stone National Historic Site, Timpanogos Cave National Monument, Tonto National Monument, Tumacacori National Historical Park, Tupelo National Battlefield, Tuskegee Airmen National Historic Site, Tuskegee Institute National Historic Site, Tuzigoot National Monument, Ulysses S. Grant National Historic Site, Upper Delaware Scenic and Recreational River, Valles Caldera National Preserve, Valley Forge National Historical Park, Vanderbilt Mansion National Historic Site, Vietnam Veterans Memorial, Virgin Islands Coral Reef National Monument, Virgin Islands National Park, Virgin Islands, Voyageurs National Park, Waco Mammoth National Monument, Walnut Canyon National Monument, War in the Pacific National Historical Park, Washington Monument, Washita Battlefield National Historic Site, Weir Farm National Historic Site, Whiskeytown-Shasta-Trinity National Recreation Area, White House, White Sands National Monument, Whitman Mission National Historic Site, William Howard Taft National Historic Site, Wilson's Creek National Battlefield, Wind Cave National Park, Wolf Trap Farm Park, Women's Rights National Historical Park, World War I Memorial, World War II Memorial, World War II Valor in the Pacific National Monument, Wrangell-St. Elias National Park, Wrangell-St. Elias National Preserve, Wright Brothers National Memorial, Wupatki National Monument, Yellowstone National Park, Yosemite National Park, Yucca House National Monument, Yukon-Charley Rivers National Preserve, Zion National Park</abstract>
<purpose>This service depicts National Park Service boundary data that was created by the Land Resources Division.</purpose>
</descript>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>boundaries</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>National Park Service</themekey>
<themekey>Park Boundaries</themekey>
<themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
<themekey>United States</themekey>
<themekey>NPS</themekey>
<themekey>National Parks</themekey>
<themekey>Federal Boundaries</themekey>
<themekey>Federal Lands</themekey>
<themekey>Land Resources Division</themekey>
<themekey>LRD</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and / or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on computer systems at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</useconst>
<datacred>National Park Service</datacred>
<native>Esri ArcGIS 12.4.0.19948</native>
</idinfo>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>0</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>NPS BOUNDARIES</enttypl>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UNIT_CODE</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GIS_Notes</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UNIT_NAME</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DATE_EDIT</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REGION</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UNIT_TYPE</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>CREATED_BY</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>METADATA</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PARKNAME</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
					<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
					<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20190708</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<!--no contact person or organization name available-->
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
